I think we're live and I think we are
dressed live on Facebook which is
perfect it's just in the game be
Facebook projects hmm someone so welcome
to solution raising I'm just going to
make sure that's not Eric they need to
join no it's something else
well look there's Eric yeah all right we
can talk for 15 minutes roughly about
what is currently being done for
community how people find it and
maintain it and what's good about it and
maybe not so good about it or anything
anyone like to start I'm happy to just
briefly introduce myself being the new
member of the group or the new
participant of the group and having only
just wrist very recently finding out
about this call diving in the deep end
so I am an artist and I'm involved in
the arts community I am one half of a
small company named legend ear in the US
and we are building an art community
around the philosophy that we call
embedded art or the embedded artist that
deals with problems related to artists
being disconnected from self
disconnected from planet disconnected
from community and the effect that this
has had on young artists that are
growing up to be illustrators or working
in entertainment and stuff like that and
so we deal with a number of issues
around these communities being stuck
behind computers being validating the
work that they do through watching other
artists on Instagram and so on and we
encourage them to get back out into the
world whether that's in nature or inner
cities or in families or in any context
but to investigate the kinds of cyclic
relationships that they're establishing
through their practice rather than going
somewhere extracting something making
art about it and showing it in a gallery
it's about actually creating
projects where that art feeds back into
the community strengthens the community
strengthens themselves physically
mentally so we're at a where quite a
beginning stage but with on running
events and building our community
directly we've done four events in
ditional in different national parks in
the US and Canada of about 50
participants each where we went out for
a week and went hiking with artists and
did a lot of talking about our
industries and how they could be better
and now because of this situation in in
alignment with our what we were already
planning to do we're kind of speeding up
our plans for our online community and
to get those people that have come to
events and who understand the philosophy
that we're we're talking about to begin
to extend those ideas outwards and offer
support the young artists and also to
support a broader community with an art
practice people that may not have a
creative outlet may not write or make
music or draw do anything like that and
right now I'm looking at the potential
for some non verbal and non intellectual
artistic modalities to be a bit of a
pressure valve for what people are going
to be going through emotionally and
psychologically over the next couple of
months so giving people just very basic
practices of how to keep a sketchbook or
a journal or you know do some
improvisation just as a way to kind of
release that energy and record their
thoughts and make sense over time so
that's a little bit about me and my
community I love that I love I love the
use of art to build community I mean I
think that's fundamentally what
community is about is doing stuff
together which feels meaningful and
worthwhile right I mean that's that's
that's that's I think not a bad
definition of what community is Kevin
and I were on a call recently we're
talking about singing as a mode for
better as a modality through which one
could build community and you know we
were actually talking about it in the
context of squashing flattening
hierarchies right because when you come
together and sing where you exist in any
particular hierarchy becomes completely
irrelevant right it takes you out of all
of that
so yeah I think art does the same thing
I'm really interested in talking to you
more Adam this is not the time and place
but I'm really interested in talking to
you more about what you're doing did we
lose do believe yeah I'm not sure she
ducked out for something or we seem to
be gaining at State the other there
there I'm playing around so I thought
that only Eric would be joining me for
this conversation because nobody else
else RSVP'd if I had known never gonna
be this many people I would have
switched it on to zoom and then we would
have broken up into two groups because
it's too hard to have this conversation
with even six people but let alone more
than s so just for everyone to know
there is a Facebook group called
solution raising and there's a
spreadsheet so we can sign up and then
we can more coordinate how to have these
conversations going to have like a fun
fun conversation for the people having
the conversation and have it be
generative which is easier with less
people so I'm gonna drop you off to zoom
right now could we don't still do that
is there any reason we couldn't just
already live online so we'll just call
this what it what it is for now and see
about the issue is Stacy's not on camera
so even if you're on the bottom I can
still see you if you raise your hand and
you have something you want to say I can
rotate us out and what they'll see how
it works so maybe we'll try to be more
succinct and more just because the
videos also when you're practicing rule
omega2 to be doing um a little bit like
the glass feed game where you're like
thinking what you're gonna say and then
say it more succinctly and not put all
the filler but you know I'm not great at
conversation so talking about we only
have 10 more minutes to talk about
what's currently happening in community
and the most which phone to what
community could look like in a better
world but so I vote I guess we can't add
Stacy now one more very very quick thing
in in terms of just putting the
community thing in context of
coronavirus this everyone having to stay
home could be really really good for
local community building it could be a
really positive officer this whole
coronavirus thing that was all I want to
say yeah I agree
before coronavirus ever hit us or at
least hit more close to home for me
community is both like where I find my
solace I have a lot of community in my
life
even before I didn't even necessarily
realize where I had community in my life
because I wanted it to look exactly like
it did online like I want our story
exactly like I did on the media like I
wanted friends I wanted I wanted friends
I wanted like six core people that hung
out together all the time even though
that's not actually conducive with my
personality but for me the difficult
part about community right now is that
it is on the individual to find it so we
have to fake our personalities to a
certain degree in order to be palatable
to the masses in order to find people so
we can be our true selves and then start
seeing are we actually compatible and I
would like I think that that is already
broken because we enjoy authentic seeing
other people and the more we're able to
be authentic and then find out are
people that we align with the better we
are going to be happier and the better
cohesion our groups are gonna have I'm
gonna let the people speak televisions
hmm so I guess what I'm doing for
community of recently has been very
online focused all right no last number
of years I became pretty like housebound
and reclusive from having been pretty
gregarious and that flowed into online
and in reaching out online here in
recent months it's turned into like an
active focus of making an effort to be
in touch and you know connect through
Facebook groups and this cords actually
been a great one for me a friend Richie
and some friends of him started a game
be parallax group a while back that a
lot of relationships formed through and
some of us have been meeting up on a
weekly and now by monthly basis on just
for personal conversations it's a
connect and form individual community
that spurred off of that and grew out of
that
and I've just found myself even just
being here for friends you know somebody
I hadn't talked to in years got hold me
the other day and had stuff on their
mind and they wanted somebody they knew
that had a philosophical bent to talk to
and you know I pop to mind and we talked
for three and a half hours or something
right now specifically we have a lot of
there's some even going around it's like
introverts put down your book and checks
all your extrovert friends they are not
doing okay and I know when I had to
start self isolating non-for virus
reasons but for mental health and
sensory reason I even though I'm an
introvert I went through a long period
of needing something some kind of human
connection and then when I would get
together with people I had like all of
this puppy energy that I was just like
putting all over everyone and so it was
a hard to find that balance of like okay
I still need some kind of outside
connection but I need to remain at home
and then finding online finding online
real community that I communicate with
online gives me the best of both worlds
because then when I do show up in the
real world in a few months when we're
all back to doing that then I can talk
about what they want to talk about and
not just saving the world and game B
type stuff because I found people to
talk about that with because it's a more
I think it's like focused I found people
to talk about my special interest with
and so I can talk about other things I
resonate with that strongly by reducing
the urgency of it in other contexts and
yeah I felt that for me I have a lot of
community that I participate in that's
not online but I but I have been moving
more towards online even prior to
coronavirus because I had that same
problem of like the people I was around
I couldn't talk about the subjects that
I wanted to you know that I was
interested in and so I would get
painfully bored and so like I just
couldn't participate in the
conversations that people wanted to
participate in real in real time but um
you know I spoken in this group in these
groups before about spending a lot of
time in like 12-step groups and that's
and how that is definitely a place where
I can go and be myself and like
show everything that's you knows
everything that's there
within these hour-long you know meetings
and there's something to be said about
that
and yesterday I got to participate in
something that was hosted by rebel
wisdom that was kind of a similar type
feel and I and I really like that
because it was talking about more than
just what we talked about in 12-step
groups and you know kind of figuring out
like how do you set you know how do you
show up authentically and with you know
bringing everything that you are into a
group and not scaring the out of
people or you know running them off and
and and how do you you know I mean art
is a tremendous way of bringing people
together suffering is another way of
bringing people together that's what you
know 12-step is is people coming
together around you know very deep
painful painful stuff and but community
like other than 12-step I haven't like
it's it's hard to and that's a very
specific format it's hard it's hard to
find community in the real world because
I it's really hard to get along with
people or let me rephrase that
I find people very annoying and but here
in this ike it's like it's a limited
amount of input and so I can handle this
I can handle being an account in a group
of six people versus in the real world I
just get flat overwhelmed and have to
run end up running away and so like
there's there's I think for a lot of
people there are a lot of a lot more
people like me introverts who actually
aren't introvert but we get overwhelmed
by being around people you know about
too much stimulus and so like this
opportunity of everybody being forced
communicate this way I think is gonna
probably change how people interact and
I like that oh sorry no you go ahead
and I I wanted to just anecdotally share
something that happened this morning
I've been doing a three-week morning
challenge pranayama breathing related
physically in a studio here in Berlin we
finished the first week and then we had
to move to online because we've entered
the semi lockdown and this morning was
the first of the online sessions and I
noticed two responses from people
there's a group of about 25 and the
first thing that came up was in the
beginning when everyone logged on
someone said this is amazing this is the
first time since we started this a week
ago that we've actually looked at each
other's faces so there was a physical
connection of coming into that studio
together every morning and you did feel
like you were there with other people
but it was only when we came online that
we actually acknowledged that we hadn't
really sat face to face and so there was
a surprising amount of connection
through that digital medium that we
didn't expect just because our heads
were close to the cameras but then the
other thing that happened was a lot of
people felt like throughout the class
they started to feel like they were
watching a YouTube video and so there
was this kind of flicking between
feeling presence of that community and
then kind of tuning out because it felt
like something pre-recorded that you
were just watching the teacher do and so
I think there's there's something really
interesting in the potential of these
crossover digital and offline things
that's even more interesting than you
know I have my my real life friends and
that I have these online communities and
they both serve these very unique
purposes there's also something that's
happening uniquely now we're very
tight-knit offline communities are
transitioning online and being like wow
this is we're sharing ideas in a new way
we're sharing documents in a new way
we're looking at each other's faces in a
new way so it's a it's a two-way street
and I think it goes both ways the other
thing just briefly to Kiera's
when you said that art is a great way to
connect and suffering also is in
building this community of artists what
I found was the does if if I was to
simplify two poles into those categories
is that we had both in that community
which is to say that we were a group of
people that bonded around a shared love
of art and the pursuit of technique and
all of these things that are fun and
exciting about art but if it was only
that then it would devolve into a kind
of an ego game and people would start to
get wrapped up and trying to impress
each other with their artworks and so
what would then spontaneously come up
would be more catharsis and more
campfire discussion and people bringing
up a lot of their fear around why am i
an artist is this useful to the world
what am I doing with my life kind of
stuff and that would sort of belt up you
go but if it went all that way and there
was nothing to to kind of congeal around
then people wouldn't stick with the
community after the events and so there
was something about coming together
around a shared love of something and
also facilitating ways for people to
open up their vulnerability and that
community of a shared interest would
sort of be a fallback and guarantee that
that community would stick together even
when people started showing all of their
their and their shadows you know it
was like well we can fall back on the
fact that we both love drawing and we
can talk about that for a while and
bring the volume down so balancing those
forces does powerfully so I should
transition into now we get it created
our beautiful world our world that is
what community would look like for the
planet or for ourselves that every want
to focus on in however long in the
future you need it to be afraid to be
feasible
five ten hundred years what does that
look like to you um my young one I've
had bumping around might had a lot for a
while now is I really really really like
the idea that pops around of the sub
Dunbar number micro-communities
like I mean it
a little bit the Dunbar number things a
little bit arbitrary is like I connect
to it for its truthiness an intuitive
connection like you know I don't know if
it's any kind of you know how well that
original study holds up or anything but
for a matter of personal aesthetic I
like it regardless of whether the
science adds up so much for that core
idea of it being a unit of people where
one can form close knowing connection
yeah oh and I see those relating to the
coronavirus stuff how like if we already
had those tight communities we would be
leaning on those right now especially
like if they were like the physical ones
organic farming out in the boonies or
something but also the urban you know
shared benefit corporation kind of idea
as well we'd be leaning on them for
support and it would also be a way to
set the wall up a little farther out
than just the nuclear family you know to
have something more than nuclear family
but still having a semi permeable
barrier to protect oneself from pandemic
concerns and so on you know tuck away
with 50 people maybe instead of five
people would be a possibility and that's
kind of a setting yeah um where that
micro community could kind of close its
gates for awhile and pull into itself
and you know live off its own food
stores and things like that for a couple
of months and still have something more
of a vibrant human village community
going on within itself and somewhere in
that you know 15 to 150 people unit you
know I imagine getting up to the higher
end of that might be problematic on the
pandemic scale but you know I think it'd
be reasonable at 25 people could kind of
cloister together and if they were you
know cutting off contact with the
external world still have a reasonable
effect on slowing down pandemic spread
yeah I like these I was thinking
actually exactly the same thing just
before you started talking Kevin I was
thinking yeah yeah yeah that's that very
very similar vision I have I would just
take it one step further and say that
those communities not only have strong
social bonds between them but also rely
on each other
again my grand vision is that each of
these communities would be so a very
large extent self-sustaining right you
know they would grow much of the most of
their own deal with their own waste
generate their own power you know all of
this kind of stuff would be done within
that community in this builds massive
resilience into the society as a whole
right because obviously communities can
share with each other as well as each
being independently you know
self-sustaining they also have the
opportunity to to share an exchange with
each other and help each other out in
hard times and all that kind of stuff so
yeah that that builds a huge amount of
redundancy and extra capacity and and
slack if you like into in into the
system to be updated to be taken up I'm
it's interesting as I was hearing you
guys talk there's there's a part of me
that really loves that idea and there's
also the reality of the lack of
emotional resilience that most people
have to live in that close of proximity
with that many people it took my husband
and I like six or seven years before we
could like work through all of our stuff
in terms of communicating with each
other to be able to not want to kill
each other at times and you know the the
amount of you know that then I think my
biggest concern is I don't know if I
could count that many people that I know
within Proximus is achill proximity of
me that have the emotional intelligence
to be able to like have the
conversations of you know in terms of
working through the emotional stuff you
know I like at what Adam was talking
about in terms of okay when when it gets
to be too much in terms of you know the
interpersonal stuff we can we
divert to you know talking about art and
I you know if if there was a situation
where somebody had a homestead or
acreage and stuff like that and like if
you couldn't hit if if for a while it's
like okay I can't talk to you right now
let's go plant from corn like then there
that there's something else to focus the
energy on but there is I mean if we're
talking about if we're talking about
Jubilees idea of you know a hundred
thousand dollars and ten thousand people
I don't know if we could even buy one
property for $100,000 so okay we're not
there yet
River talking to about our ideal in the
future oh and you know what does your
ideal in the future look like for you
for community kara okay what what does
my ideal look like for me in the future
that's um so I was skipping ahead a step
sorry that's for me it's I think
something similar along those lines i I
think for me technology plays more of a
role in it and I don't know quite what
that how that plays into it um and yeah
my ideal I think it you know there's
definitely something about communal
living there is definitely something
about being more in touch with nature
but there's also the inclusion of
technology and you know looking at maybe
looking at Quakers as a model I'm I'm
not yeah that's one where I'm having I I
have a hard time committing to what it
is that I the what my ideal is unless an
interesting thing for me to observe so
yeah I think that is also it having lots
of for me it's still having a lot of
possibility because I know there are
things that I want to like I really want
this and then I get it and it's like
wait no no I actually don't want this
and I think community especially is that
for a lot of people they think
they want intentional community and then
they're in it and it's a lot of work
it's a lot of emotional work and
interrelated work that you don't like
you can't control other people and so
what are you gonna what are you going to
build a community around and having for
me it's having diversity of communities
so not just my community but I know I
can always leave and therefore I'm
willing to stay and so also having a
Dunbar community size that I would like
to have is also focused on technical
creating technology just because that's
what I'm here to do but I know there's a
pro and con towards having like a game
be community then if you drop game B or
you dropped for the community right or
vice versa
and but having an ace a place that I
live and eat and play with so that when
something like the Khurana buyers
happens we can insulate when someone
goes traveling it comes back we can
quarantine them and at the same time
being able to connect to people online
and to have my special interests I can
talk about or to connect over a very my
new part that I might I might be into
and so to be able to have these like
what does it make what makes sense to me
to live in community maybe I'm a golf
feeding person I'm not but maybe
and so I I love horses so I'd love to be
around horses even though I'm not a
Whore like I've never had a horse I
wouldn't know how to care for one by
myself but having access to a horse I
would love that and so I would look for
a community that has that my daughter
would probably love that too she want a
dance studio so they look for that and
then I would find people online to make
technology with or it's been to do a
project with and to be able to easily
find any kind of community whether it's
an artistic community at whatever level
you're at whether it's a sporting
community and being able to coordinate
my life so I can have these interactions
but also I personally want a small
insulated group of people just because
that's how I want to build relationships
I want more deeper relationships with a
few people rather than a surface level
with a bunch of people and I want them
in person and I want them online sorry
that reminds me of something Kyra was
saying before about being able to bring
everything you are to your community and
it got it just made me think it in in
the time this is what you've said just
reminds me made me think in the moment
that I guess it depends on what you mean
by community by community do you mean
like the one community in
which you live in geographically because
really we are members of multiple
communities right and so you don't
necessarily need to bring everything you
are to all of them right the some of
them gives you what you need and you
know that you see what I mean that don't
have to rely on one for everything is
the point and equally it doesn't have to
expect everything of you do it now go
for it you know I was just thinking that
we quite often find ourselves in
physical proximity communities
involuntarily so you know we moved into
an apartment building and suddenly we're
in a building with a bunch of people
that we we have no idea who they are we
didn't choose them there was no there
was no social contract there at all or
as an artist many times I've moved into
big shared studios again you know I
found a space that was the right price I
have no idea who else is in there
and where I spend all of my time doing
the thing that I'm passionate about I
may or may not want to be around those
people artistically speaking so I think
that what the online world has given us
is this gigantic selection of people
from which we can compose our own
entirely voluntary interactive group and
then we're still in this messy offline
world where we have to deal with all of
these people that we have no Sara Lee
like-minded relationship with so I can
see an ideal future where I can split my
world into two downbar groups there's a
Dunbar group that I choose based on
wanting to live with them but having a
wide variety of personality types and
interests and there's my online Dunbar
group which may also be from a wide
variety of interests but it's connected
around the things that are important to
me and that online my my individual
online Dunbar 100 or 150 does not have
to be shared between that 150 people I
can be one of a completely different
Dunbar group for that individual which
doesn't work if you're creating a
physical community and so I think
there's two different structures that
you're building there one is how do I
limit this massive online selection to a
group that's that's really in line with
what I'm trying to do and then how do I
expand myself offline to be able to
interact with very different individuals
in a local community two different
challenges I like that I think it's not
important to in that it adds a extra
layer of anti fragility the online
network helps build some kind of meta
layer of connections like when you have
fibers biased in different directions to
form a stronger you know like they do
with that building plywood where they
put the different grain of the wood
alternating directions because it's
stronger overall that way you get some
kind of a layered you know different
biases interconnecting and so it takes
it helps absorb one can help absorb
stresses from the other and distribute
them and it makes the whole network more
anti fragile overall and all larger
community of community since I think UTS
is having them not be so insular that
people aren't connecting outside I think
people have to connect outside those
insular communities to some extent just
for the survival of those insular
communities and of humanity as a whole
you know it can't be just disappear and
pretend the world doesn't exist right I
would not want to be living in a group
of 150 people with one doctor unless
that one doctor was connected to another
hundred and fifty doctors who could
share some ideas hmm yeah absolutely and
having that one physical location you
can do things like insulate yourself
from a pandemic or just any you know
even the flu be like no when you come
back you are in a house for a week can
you take care of you and that's part of
if you decide to travel you're doing
this and then some communities might be
no all the international people live
here and we're jet setters and we're all
over the place
where the disease vectors for the world
but at least they're not because right
now our complexity our
interconnectedness that we don't even
understand is showcasing all of our
fragility and all of our that like even
my community that is absolutely amazing
they're the ones who've taken the most
steps forward they cancel their common
meals for a month they're having an
online meeting this Thursday to discuss
it even though they're five feet away
from each other right there and
talking about counsel in the playroom
they're looking after each other they're
able to have that capacity to do that
but there's four nurses who live there
there's you know I mean everyone's still
leaving and going to their work the kids
are still if they're on spring break but
you know they go to different schools
and so having an enslaved community that
you play with eat with learn with and
then having outside connected
communities that are hey I have my
special interests here you go and play
sports and stuff but you're also you can
pull it back and if there's something
going around and I I went over to the 30
minutes I'm sure that I like this having
a place to retreat to being yeah and so
now we can move on to the adjacent
possible which we give the majority of
the time to so what could we actually do
right now in the world if we had 10,000
people and $100,000 we are we talking
about we have 10,000 people to work on a
project or we're doing something with
those 10,000 people so 10,000 people
work here a project we're pretty
difficult but it's it's solving it for
those 10,000 people so 10,000 members
10,000 customers 10,000 people that are
involved at some level in funding it
that's where the hundred thousand 10,000
is for 10,000 people to put in ten
dollars it's not gonna break the bank
but they're probably not going to do the
work they're not gonna want to do the
work it'll be maybe a 10,000 putting in
money a hunt and having conversations
and doing surface level work 100 doing
actual work and maybe 10 doing full-time
paid work yeah I mean based on that kind
of model I think I think you could
something that seems an experimentation
is always is always key to my thinking
right and with $100,000 we tend to I
mean not all 10,000 people could
actually participate in the experiment
right but they could fund it and they
could observe it they could comment on
it and suggest and and and so on but you
you could you could define a set of
parameters characteristics goals
whatever it might be and and that is
what you build a community around I
think that notion of being able to step
away from the interpersonal stuff and
just have to get on with right and
come back to that later when you've all
had time to off-gas I think that's
really really important so having a
thing whatever it is be it
upbeat music permaculture it doesn't
matter whatever is a bit but have a
clear thing you know that it's built
around and then you know the the
strategies are all aligned to that
central mission if you like and and
experiment with it and see what works
and what doesn't and $100,000 I think
allows you to run that experiment with
say 50 people write something like that
50 people 20 households something in
something on that kind of scale and and
and just see what you can do just see
what you can do I didn't quite
understand that what are the 50 people
doing living living together in a
community
ah I was giving some thought to this
came up in conversation with a friend
relational in a way on how I've
envisioned possible like doing a
transition be oriented community as a
research project you know we're
literally have the people that are in it
commit to like Big Brother journaling
and and even things like we're gonna try
this decision-making method for six
months then we're gonna try a different
decision-making method and compare and
contrast and you could I even I think
incorporate it there might be advantages
to even officially having an academic
somebody that studies people systems
whether it be Dave Snowden or but either
ROI or whoever you know have somebody
that's already like God academic
standing even writing it up you know and
framing it and getting academic grants
and stuff for it bring in as well as the
ten dollars per 10,000 people also see
if you can just pull in some straight-up
you know grant funding money for it and
and put somewhere in the 15 to 50 or
whatever people in some kind of coaling
situation and yeah and then record it
and learn from their iterations can I
ask out of the five people over here cuz
Stacy's on mute cell is um
weather would you be one of the non
fifty would you want to fund other
people to live in the fifty like which
side of that do you want to be on how do
you envision yourself participating
if we win 10 bucks then yes and just
because I'm not one of the 50 does not
mean I'm not participating right I am
I'm involved in the experiment you know
I'm a curious interested party who will
offer my comments observations
suggestions criticisms etc of what's
going on along with everybody else I
mean that's part of being the 10,000
right is you're involved in this
experiment even though you may not be
one of the 50 that's actually living it
up with that I would say I would not
want to be one of the fifty because I
would not want to have 950 other people
the other people being able to have an
input on how the 50 people live their
lives like it would be inviting to nine
hundred and fifty nine thousand nine
hundred fifty people they would be
contributing $10 and the the 50 people
would would be you give like I would I
would only want to participate if that
meant that the 50 people were autonomous
and other people were not giving their
input on that other people were more a
YouTube channel where they passively
kick in but they don't have
decision-making power but they can still
offer suggestions but then but then the
thing that comes to mind is like this or
what came to mind add from that
description was hello MTV the TV show
like I agreed to send into that I agree
that is a dangerous Adam looks like yeah
something so what if you were to split
out those parts of the process and you
said okay we need our privacy and our
autonomy to live this experiment out but
we need 9950 backers at $10 h and your
buy-in is $10 and along with that you
make some brief succinct recommendations
for how you think this experiment should
run we collect all of that aggregate
that data formulate the experiment
through that with in agreement with the
50 people that say yes we're all
comfortable to try this right and then
and then what you get back at the end is
proper well-documented research okay we
ran the experiment this is how the
community worked who are the problems we
encountered and that information is
given back as your reward for
kick-starting this experiment and maybe
even quarterly updates or something you
know like some I think updates would be
yeah I was feeling like atom two is like
I was thinking along those lines a bit
too is having the initial stage not have
the two concurrent have the first
bringing people in and then committing
to because oh also part of it that the
attend thousand could take part in would
be like you know finding site location
and helping research zoning and you know
like I'd like to try building a
compressed earth house you know but
that's gonna be finding a county where
the zonings
you know see this is to me I think
actually that level is actually what we
would want to do with ten thousand
people at a hundred thousand dollars
because I wouldn't want to find other
people like I want to live in that
community and I want to be part of that
first of all there's hundreds of
intentional communities around the world
right now and there's thousands that
have been tried and failed and so
getting those people together to have a
conversation and the experiments already
been run so asking what worked what
didn't work what decision-making policy
and all of that seems like more
effective than watching this community
fall apart and do its own thing for
however long it's it's able to do that
but having if we're talking about
concentrating almost physical
communities having a resource to be able
to say hey I how do we find a group of
how do we find our 50 people we're gonna
have to put in way more than ten dollars
to form our community right you have to
put in $10,000 or $100,000 or how do we
fund it but how do I find people to
create a community with what are we
creating it around how do we decide on
what kind of shelter to create what how
do we decide on plumbing and how do we
decide on what is out there right now
and what's best how does OE work in my
province versus your state right like
how do we actually create the
information sharing and resources the
infrastructure to find and create
in me Eric there's another way we could
utilize the tenth L the 10,000 people in
this group as well Kevin said something
which made me think this that you know
in that group of ten thousand people
will be all kinds of people with
expertise in all kinds of things right
how to make automatic composting toilets
and and and and and turn that into
fertilizer and how to purify your water
and how to heat your blah blah blah blah
blah blah blah right and so these people
could a contribute technology and ideas
for technology and actual stuff in
addition to their ten dollars and
remember it's not every single person
paying exactly ten dollars right it's
you invite contributions and some people
contribute more than others and in this
sphere also some people will contribute
more than others some people will
actually give you stuff which you can
use in the community you know what I
mean with it and so you know the hundred
thousand dollar startup cash you've got
would be something that supplement to a
very large extent by stuff that people
will give you to crack on and use and
experiment with how it goes right it's
not just the engineering of the
community as a whole there's also
hundreds and hundreds of sub experiments
in you know the actualities of living
you know the engine the physics and
engineering of living which need to be
undertaken as well right techniques
which need to be refined and improved
and blah blah blah so yeah III still
don't know I completely agree with you
that there's going to be clamoring to be
one of the 50 there's gonna be way more
than 50 who want to be one of the fifty
I I completely agree with that and some
kind of selection process and some
people are going to resent the fact that
they didn't get selected and all of that
I agree is a problem with this I I
accept all of that but nevertheless I
still think that community of 10,000
would have a really significant
contribution to make in an ongoing way
right because one of the things that
might come out of the community is our
plumbing system doesn't work right for
whatever reason because of this terrain
blah blah blah we've run across this
problem you put that out to the
community and you got nice nice yeah
when the community when the test
community has problems they can
crowdsource to the PS large code
interest sauce I want to hang on away
possibly to avoid that selection process
uncomfortable this
ah one way to avoid that selection
process uncomfortableness might be for
the 50 to come together in the first
place and then present the project right
from the very beginning as we this 50
are asking for patrons that are
interested in this experiment we would
like to hold and then it's already done
and there's no fighting for a slot you
know one the same sense of ownership
though sorry I don't even racing
throughout I do apologize a problem at
all
my my first thought because of just
everything that's happening at the
moment when this question came up my
mind just jumps to technology to apps to
this online communication thing where
all of the innovations going and it
jumps there because I think $100,000
we're talking about physically setting
up a community those numbers don't match
to me so ok like like if we can't do
anything physical with a hundred
thousand dollars what can we build with
that that will then flow into something
physical so in my mind I see 100
thousand dollar build a platform for
10,000 people a digital platform which
is a dunbar of Dunbar's 100 groups of
100 people each each of those 100 groups
takes a problem that needs to be solved
for a large sustainable network of
communities so imagine 100 communities
spread out among different countries
with a hundred people each from mixed
professions but it begins with 100
groups of 100 people in each profession
problem solving what what does it take
to run these communities cooling all of
those solutions so a solution for
sanitation a solution to education
learnt the food all of these groups
focusing on that the results are all
pulled together and then those
communities of 100 can start to form
geographically and begin their own
funding mechanisms and say we now have
not only a group of 100 people that are
ready to come together and form a
community but each one of those 100
people give or take is connected to an
active group of a hundred people around
the world all focused on that part of
community building and it's the platform
that's the key here
which
collect information which which holds
the accountability which gives the proof
of concept I love that atom I think that
was I don't even want to change the
topic now cuz I was shopping around an
idea that is very similar to that for
about well I but actively shopping the
idea around for about six weeks the
overall dream of it little goes back a
little farther but I like the idea of
incorporating something as a class-b
benefit corporation or nonprofit and
calling it the pet name I've had for it
is becoming be becoming be incorporated
and the idea for that stirred around the
software platform I think to start with
would be to leverage something called
MediaWiki which is the software which
wikipedia uses you can do more than just
an information with you with the
software it has a fairly extensive
social interaction element under the
hood that the editors of Wikipedia used
to interact with each other that could
be brought more to the forefront and
made a side-by-side thing with the
information sharing in a way to where
you can leverage both the hub to store
information and also a hub to interact
and form relationships one could have
those
what were you saying like 200 silos of
100 or the different little subgroups
one could do those of subdomains within
a central wiki they could each then
branch off and have their own separate
server which is still linked to the
course or server as things grow I had
originally envisioned it as becoming
more of a sort of a meaning hub in the
first place but then I started thinking
about the hands on people that actually
are doing attempts at intentional
community and are doing ecological like
house building and da-da-da-da-da and
how it would be nice to bring them in
with the meaning space people as well
where I was imagining this MediaWiki
instance called meaning hub I've now
been thinking of calling it being hub
and incorporate a wider variety of
people into its original foundation
with the understanding that as it grows
it will branch out into people having
their own freestanding semi-autonomous
servers which still have a relationship
with the central hub you know which to
link to and share information and have a
bit of elbow running and chats and stuff
there and part of that was to facilitate
people forming actual real world
community as part of the idea of this as
well as facilitating idea exchange my
idea was if I get like game be having a
sub-domain
and also integral having a sub-domain
and the portal having a sub-domain and
meta modernism having a sub-domain and
this group of people in like what the
open source ecology project say having a
subdomain yada yada yada if you get
these starting from this central place
and then you know diversifying a bit out
from there it's going to help facilitate
a higher percentage of relationships in
physical reasonable proximity like I
don't like like those ideas Kevin but
also I want to concentrate on like not
the technology sorry I'll get it done
it's generating the dream of what 200
bucks if anybody would like the original
incarnation I'm getting ready to do it
on a computer in my house as an example
but if I would love to skip that step
and go straight to a shared cloud server
if somebody wants to help crowd fund the
200 bucks and make this happen
Belva Kathy that's my challenge to
everybody listing it like I love the
tech solutions but I love the idea of
the hundreds hundred because one you
just need the first hundred to kind of
talk about fighting the other hundred
like everybody we each 500 people or how
do we grow this to be bigger then how do
we keep growing it to be bigger because
technology can solve many of our complex
problems but if we don't have that
10,000 people we haven't solved it right
we can't easily get a hundred thousand
we can't split it into 100 and so
technology's not the problem it's how do
you actually get a group of people to
know that this thing exists how do you
get
how do you build from there but I think
this 100 hundred is like so many people
want to live in community how do we
start from that place right of like
getting 10,000 people watching this
video right or getting 10,000 people to
participate in this type of conversation
or how do we like yeah so I think there
are two problems that this solves and I
think that there's an existing way that
we can approach collecting this
community the first problem is if you
take a an intentional community and you
look at all of the different reasons
that they have their life cycle and
eventually fall apart one is how do you
get the right distribution of people
with enough expertise to make that
community self-sufficient and this
solves that by saying you don't need to
have a hundred doctors you need to have
one doctor connected to another 99
doctors and to share that expertise the
other problem is how much power and
sovereignty can we wield as a group of a
hundred or 150 people on our land and
all of the problems to do with land
ownership and government and everything
that comes up around a community of that
size that doesn't have the power to to
fight back or to maintain stability and
so you're solving these things you're
saying well we have physical community
with a network and we can actually say
we're a community of 10,000 where
physically distributed but there's
10,000 of us that can get behind
something that needs to be done in an
emergency we can pull resources we can
you know I don't know how that would
work legally and everything like that
but I'm sure that 10,000 people
connected with some kind of social
contract makes a much bigger difference
than 150 and so potentially a place that
you can start is existing intentional
communities and intentional communities
that are about to start up and say don't
stop what you're doing don't change to
our project keep doing what you're doing
but join this group of 10,000 so that
you can start to link up all of these
communities each of which physically is
going to have their own modus operandi
their own particular set of interests
some will be more environmental some
will be more creative and so on but say
you know get all of your people that are
in that community
into one of these subgroups around
whatever it is that they're passionate
about and start distributing those ideas
to this bigger group and I think 10,000
is a perfect kind of limit on the number
of people that could network online in
these small groups and still say we are
a network of communities there is 100
communities of a hundred people each
approximately does that make sense you
could even have because I don't know if
there's a hundred problems that need to
be solved there probably are is having
like redundancy right so you're on a
group of ten and there's ten groups
working on that problem and so you're
sharing interieur you're working as a
more cohesive unit and then you're also
connected with other ones and/or you're
on different circles right so maybe I'm
on marketing if marketing is a thing
right how do we end it is how do we
attract people for our community when we
have it and then it all the plumbing one
right and so I might be on multiple ones
that are within my capacity to be on
them within my interest and because
maybe that group of ten meets at Tuesday
and I can meet with this one but not
this one right and the more you're able
to break it down but bring it back
together as a cohesive whole for funding
and information I love this yeah the
only the only consideration with that is
that if you if you do allow too much
overlap then you've lost the cohesion of
the dunbar thing right because then all
of a sudden you're in a big group of
10,000 and you're in eighteen different
check groups and so you've lost that
feeling of like right I'm one of a one
group inside a larger group so I can see
some kind of process of checking in with
these other groups but I think it's also
important to say like okay we are a
group of a hundred and our problem to
solve is food security that's it like
that's my focus and I'm sacrificing a
little bit of my interest in other areas
in this context in order to really make
sure that I'm solving that problem for
the community and then maybe there's an
open forum for the arts group that I say
you know I'm really also interested in
that but I'm not responsible for it but
I'd love to be there at that open forum
to talk to meet those people to talk
about their ideas to throw in some ideas
but I know what I'm responsible for i've
got clear marching orders and i know
what
problems I need to solve but if I may if
you're responsible for say food security
then part of that is going it's
necessarily going to be interfacing with
waste management water production and
you know what I mean you know there's
gonna have to be and so I understand
you've got yeah I completely understand
what you're saying about distributing
your attention to widely so you can't
actually get on with the thing that is
your primary goal but distributing your
attention appropriately because it
informs the thing that you're you know
it forms your core purpose that that has
to be done right yeah I think
personalities that tend to cross um like
I do this and I've noticed it's as part
of social networks that I've been in
like um this arts activism and music
scene I used to be at in Columbus Ohio
um I was one of a hand you know what's
more than a handful maybe but well
whatever one of the few one of the
smaller percentage that crossed a lot of
like nodes like I had punk friends I had
goth friends I had hippie friends I had
you know like classical music friends I
had Food Not Bombs friends hemp campaign
fan you know all these different little
like small tight-knit little clusters of
community in this various overlapping
scenes I was one of the small percentage
of people that crossed into lots of
different ones you know like ran along
the liminal spaces in-between and made
interconnections and introduced people
between those communities and
transferred information between those
communities I think there are other
people like me that tend to do that um
what we can do in a network of community
of communities nested communities is you
can have the people within the group
that are tend to be a little more
outreach broadly gregarious or broadly
collecting interest um you could let
them kind of be a facilitator that
speaks a bit for that note you've got
ten people working on the food security
issue one of them can kind of touch base
with a group of you know five other
people that come from groups they're
also looking at food security from
different angles and stay in touch on a
shared page where they post updates and
key
a little bit of like a contact with each
other to know a little bit of you of
what all five groups are doing you know
and so not everybody in the group has to
be looking outward to the other groups
that are working on food security you
can have individuals that are naturally
personality inclined to do so take
responsible for building that inner mesh
network the mycelium that connects the
forest floor and moves resources when
information from one part to the other
yeah that might be its own
problem-solving group is a hundred
people who are like hey we're the
interconnected part and you're trying to
figure out how do we bring in the
information from plumbing and food
safety and I got goose bumps on that
Jubilee thank you yeah you know what I
what I would love like if I just think
about this right now in this situation
with all the energy that I had to want
to do something where is that blocked
where could that be be more clearly
transferred what I wouldn't love to have
for ten dollars input is an app that I
could open up and it had my group of 100
people that I'd chosen around the things
that I'm passionate about and I could
see what they were doing I knew what my
problem was that I was focusing on I
knew who I was connected to and I said
whether these people are sharing the
same group as I am or not there's 100
people here that I can limit this
massive social choice to and I'm gonna
keep checking in with them and they
might be all working on different things
but it's some kind of limiting function
that's like they I have a relationship
around my problem-solving with each of
these people and 100 is more than enough
relationships to focus on to maintain my
focus on my goal and so that that like
give me that right now so that I can
focus and I think that that's what
everyone's looking for now is how can I
help and how can I make sure that my
energy isn't going into many different
ways and that what I do is actually
useful my first thought was like that
could be done quick as a webpage but
having it as a free-standing
app means you can hop on without the
distraction of extra browser tabs and
stuff like
it's a little more focused it might be
something where one could start really
okay even within the wiki software I was
talking one could do that as a
free-standing page and make it as a node
within wiki software when they forgot a
page and then some I'm just gonna pull
you back from your technologies you only
have like three more yeah I know that's
how your mind goes and I love it I'm
like cuz you're gonna be the one of
people who actually solves it and is
able to like create it when we get onto
the like at a different level here right
okay yeah yeah and so would anyone like
to give some closing thoughts on like
this is possible every one of these we
come up with something that's amazingly
possible with 10,000 people at $100,000
already connected to everybody except
Adam so I want to invite Adam to get in
touch on Facebook discord whatever how
do we how do I find you once we get off
the call here are you in the game big
group on Facebook yes I'll find you
there okay cool all right and everyone
if you want to participate in these we
have I started a Facebook group last a
few days ago called solution magazine so
that I'll hopefully we will know how
many people are participating and then
we can do things like break out onto
zoom because it's about having the
conversation I would love to record them
and provide them to the world so people
can see what is possible but the main
part is how do we have a conversation
that's generative and then we'll start
having the conversations up like great
now how do we make it look how do we
actually create one of these things now
we will do a solution raising on
solution raising like what are we
currently doing ideal world what could
we do at the tangent with the possible
maybe that's our first project we
actually actually concert on but I kind
of gave my own closing statements any
one spark of an idea what if we had a
social media way you were limited to 100
friends that's all I'll say and you had
to choose those people wisely other than
that this has been my first online sense
making call and I just want to thank you
all for welcoming me into that world and
introducing yourselves all today yeah
thank you I don't know if we really
introduced ourselves sorry about that
but more focused Eric did you want to
yeah two very very quick thoughts
firstly excellent call really enjoyed it
thought it was a genuinely constructive
and generative call and secondly I don't
know if any of the 20 the rest of you
but one notion which has been sort of
tacitly accepted throughout is the idea
of the Dunbar sized community right we
all that we all seem to explicitly or
tacitly agree with that notion so yeah I
found that very interesting that seems
to be an unquestioned truth somehow now
whether it's just painted as Jamie
describes it or whether there is
actually an actual thing I'm down with
it as an aesthetic whether it holds up
in an academic research or not you know
well there is there is academic
underpinning I do know something about
Dunbar's research and it is to do with
frontal lobe size in relation to overall
brain size therefore so there is an
actual underpinning it is it's not an
arbitrary number and watching so thank
you I don't have you know that I had I
had some various thoughts about you know
in terms of personality profiling and
stuff like that and but in but I think
there's there's more to be had on this
conversation so I've looked
participating in more of it Stacy I saw
you just unmuted did you want to say
something yeah I just wanted it was
really a wonderful call I'm sorry I'm
really sick I'm really feeling sick so
it was nice to come here to listen to
and say it again coronavirus you know
what it is it seriously could be I was
sick two weeks ago for about eight days
but at the time they were still saying
that you could only get the corona virus
if you had travelled so I figured okay
then this can't be it Reavers and so by
senses you say it again leave her in a
coffin is it the right symptoms fever in
a coffin now no I do have a clock
this would be the second time around but
I've been but I was doing I was cleaning
out my house and I was up in the attic
so the breathing I thought could be from
the insulation and the dust so I don't
know what I have but today I feel really
weak so I'm staying I'm staying on the
couch is there anything I want to say
about the conversation then we can stop
going live and then we can have more of
that ongoing yeah not always wonderful
thank you I hope I would like to
continue it another time yeah absolutely
thanks Stacey so I will say good bye D
well I guess face YouTube it's on
YouTube it's blue with the T so it
confused me alright bye YouTube